Yogeshwar Murugan

Senior Blockchain Engineer

yogeshwar_1997@hotmail.com • +91 9597855459
https://www.linkedin.com/in/yoga07 • https://www.github.com/yoga07

Summary

Senior Blockchain Engineer with over 5 years of experience in designing and engineering decentralized computing technology in AGILE environments. Sound in Application and Product engineering, Systems Engineering, Software Lifecycle, Algorithmic programming, and mission-critical Problem-solving backed by academic training in Software Engineering and Data Science. 'Change is the only constant' – Loves to stay current on the best practices in the industry.

Skills

Rust • High-performance Systems Engineering • P2P Networking • Consensus Algorithms • Tokenomics • Blockchain • Logic Programming • Protocol Development • CI/CD • Cloud Deployments • Test-nets releases

Work Experience

Blockchain Engineer

September 2022 - Present

Zenotta AG • Full-time

Remote

Technologies: Rust • Logic Programming • Protocol development • LLVM • AWS • Docker • CI/CD

- Research and development of the network's Data Protocol involving whitepaper development.
- Designed, implemented, and deployed intricate core network and blockchain modules from the ground up in Rust, which involves P2P network engineering, Multi-threaded Systems programming, Consensus algorithm development, Network APIs development and System performance optimizations.
- Spear-headed multiple upgrades and releases of the network on AWS which consequently opened
 the flood gates for the investors and community to take part in the test-nets. These upgrades primarily
 focused on improving the scalability and reliability of the network whilst maintaining
 performance.
- Encapsulating and packaging of client-run binaries into easily scalable, upgradeable, and distributable containers via **Docker** and **bare-metal AWS nodes.** These were used by the investors and community during test-net runs with a high-degree of success supporting multiple platforms.

Full-Stack Engineer: Decentralized Tech

May 2020 – Aug 2022

MaidSafe • Full-time

Remote

Technologies: Rust • Cryptography • Distributed systems architecture • Algorithm development • ELK Stack • Digital Ocean • CI/CD

- Designed, implemented, tested, and deployed decentralized networking and cryptocurrency features
 for the SAFE Network involving P2P networking, Data distribution and dispersion, Cryptography,
 and technical aspects of Tokenomics.
- Envisioned, implemented, and configured ELK servers and Beat services for test-nets that are hosted on Digital Ocean providing easy readability and solid insights on the network's stability and efficiency.
- Hosted and supported multiple public test-nets that are prominently used by a ~4000-member strong SAFE Network Community. Analyzed and presented insights to issues that the test-nets face on granular levels and provided resolutions for the upcoming iterations of the Network.

MaidSafe • Full-time Chennai. India

Technologies: Rust • Distributed systems • Systems programming • Application architecture and development

- Worked on multiple Client facing libraries, designing and implementing network communication
 modules and user facing APIs. Redesigned a multi-language bindings generator that parses
 native Rust APIs to generate FFI (Foreign Function Interface) bindings for C, C#, and Java. This
 paved way for user of SAFE Network's developer community with various programming language
 backgrounds to easily use SAFE Network's Client APIs.
- Extensively researched and implemented multiple flavors of data structures that are used in the SAFE Network. Various semantics such as CRDT (Conflict-free Replicated Data Types), Versioning and Immutability were incorporated within those types making the network operations more reliable, fault tolerant and versatile.

Research Intern

May 2018 - Sep 2018 • 4 mos.

CSIR-CEERI • Internship

Chennai, India

Technologies: Python 3.x • MATLAB • Signal processing • Fractal Analysis

CEERI is a constituent laboratory of the Council of Scientific and Industrial Research under the Govt.of India. Worked as a part of a research team headed by senior scientists on Fractal Analysis of Heart Rate Variability which involved collection and analysis of approx. ~2000 ECG datasets with Python and MATLAB involving multi-Fractal analysis methods which were later presented to Samsung Electronics Co. Ltd. by the organization.

Deep Learning Intern

Dec 2017 - May 2018 • 5 mos.

Nokia • Internship Chennai, India

Technologies: Python 3.x • Tensorflow • Machine learning • Internet of things • Augmented reality

Implemented and delivered multiple machine learning projects, specifically on Image Recognition and Object Detection Models that aided the IC manufacturing and security teams. Notable projects are PPE Kit recognition, Emergency exit obstacle detection, and AR machinery detection with an avg. accuracy of 85%.

Mini-Projects

Real-time Sentiment Analysis and Visualization of tweets using Spark Oct 2017

Oct 2017 – Dec 2017 • 2 mos.

3 coworkers

Technologies: Apache Spark • Maven • Twitter API • ELK

A **Sentiment Analysis Tool** that picks up specified data from Twitter via provided hashtags and analyzes their sentiment. Sentiment for each tweet was calculated based on **AFINN** dictionary and the statistics were **visualized in real-time on a dashboard**. This project was created for **ITMR-HTC**, **Chennai**.

Voice Bot for Automating Loan Application and Intake

Sep 2017 - Dec 2017 • 3 mos.

3 coworkers

Technologies: RasaNLU • BotKit • AngularJS

A voice bot designed for automating loan application and intake processes. Drastically reduced the man hours spent doing this manually and the bot was integrated with the organization's website. This project was also created for ITMR-HTC, Chennai.

Education

Bachelor's degree: (B.E) Computer Science Engineering

Aug 2015 – May 2019 • 3 yrs. 9 mos.

Sri Venkateswara College of Engineering Chennai, TAMIL NADU, India

GPA: 7.5/10

High school diploma: Physics, Chemistry and Math

Jun 2013 – May 2015 • 1 yr. 11 mos.

St Patrick's Anglo Indian Higher Secondary School Chennai, India Score: 90%

Accolades

- Share Options worth of INR 50lakhs (as of 22/09/2019) was awarded by MaidSafe, Ayr, Scotland under EMI as a recognition of performance during the period worked.
- 2nd Place among 52 contesting teams in an Inter-College Symposium for the project on "Data Mining and Analysis using Hadoop and Apache Hive"
- "Certification of Excellence" for the project "Voice bot for Vehicle Loans" by ITMR- HTC,
 Guindy
- Organized and conducted various events and workshops for "INTERRUPT 2K17" at Sri Venkateswara College of Engineering

Certifications

Data Analyst Nanodegree - Udacity

May 2018